Gregory Ryan

Junior Software Developer Profile

developergregryan@gmail.com • (716) 228-8608 <u>LinkedIn URL</u> • Boston, MA

GitHub: www.github.com/GRy82

Technologically advanced and motivated individual with relevant skills and education in managing the full software development lifecycle – from concept through delivery of next-generation applications and customizable solutions. Broad knowledge in object-oriented programming concepts, programming languages, web application frameworks, relational databases, NoSQL databases. Articulate communicator with excellent interpersonal skills; foster and fortify productive relationships with key clients, colleagues, and senior management. Bringing a strong focus on "voice of the customer" into the software development function to ensure product and customer success. Licensed Physical Therapist bringing experience and perspective from working within healthcare.

Education

Doctor of Physical Therapy SUNY at Buffalo, May 2016

 Musculoskeletal, Neuromuscular, Cardiopulmonary, Integumentary

CS50's Introduction to Computer Science Certificate

- HarvardX, October 2020
- Final project featured in CS50x gallery

Full Stack Software Development Certificate

devCodeCamp, February 2021

- 104% average on individual projects, attaining all possible bonus points
- 101% average overall, graduating top of the cohort
- Selected by instructors to lead cohort's group capstone
- Co-leader of extracurricular whiteboard sessions for current graduates

Work Experience

Physical Therapist | Joint Ventures Physical Therapy, November 2019 -October 2020

- Evaluation and treatment
- Utilizing Electronic Medical Record
- Customer outreach

Therapy Team Leader | Patriot All Pro PT, August 2017 - November 2019

- Managing care plans of 60-90 active patients at a given time
- Orchestration of educational workshops for PTA's and PT aides

Physical Therapist | McAuley Residence, July 2016 - August 2017

- Interdisciplinary rounding
- · Patient discharge planning
- Training of patient families
- · Ordering Durable Medical Equipment

Technical Proficiencies

Programming Languages: JavaScript, C#, Java, Python, Lua

Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

Libraries/Frameworks: .NET core, Entity Framework, Node.js, Express.js, React.js

Databases: SQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB

Web Services/API's: RESTful API, JSON, Postman API-testing

Testing: Unit Testing, Integration Testing, TDD, Jest

Key Projects

AutonoFit

Overview: Generates a randomized, yet appropriate exercise routine based on the user's fitness goals, their time constraints, and the equipment they possess. Do a one-time workout, or progress through a program.

Technologies: C#, ASP.NET core MVC, REST API

Features:

- Progressing reps and rest times until new exercise intensity is reached.
- Integrating lifting and cardio workout components at appropriate volumes and frequencies
- Mimicking clinical judgment of a specialist to prevent overtraining and injury.

Poolball

Overview: Sports/billiards video game adaptation. Win this fast-paced game by defending your pockets and by scoring on your opponent's to unlock features.

Technologies: Lua, Löve 2d game engine, Aseprite, Ableton Live 9.0

Features:

- Al computer player with behavior varying by difficulty mode.
- 2-dimensional collision physics achieved with implementation of physics and trigonometry.
- Original pixel artwork, animation, and music production.